<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
    <channel>
        <title>The Metron Project Blog</title>
        <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog</link>
        <description>The Metron Project Blog</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:53:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>https://validator.w3.org/feed/docs/rss2.html</docs>
        <generator>https://github.com/jpmonette/feed</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 2023 Update]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/december-2023-update</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/december-2023-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 14:53:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Issues Indexed]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="issues-indexed">Issues Indexed</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://metron.cloud/">Metron Project</a> had a total of <strong>10,722</strong> issues added to its database during December bring
the total number of issues to <strong>98,684</strong>. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="2023-database-statistics">2023 Database Statistics</h2>
<p>We added the following number of entries during 2023:</p>
<ul>
<li>Users: <strong>319</strong></li>
<li>Publishers: <strong>33</strong></li>
<li>Series: <strong>2,430</strong></li>
<li>Comics: <strong>44,914</strong></li>
<li>Characters: <strong>7,082</strong></li>
<li>Creators: <strong>3,118</strong></li>
<li>Teams: <strong>691</strong></li>
<li>Arcs: <strong>521</strong></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="htmx-and-streaming-html">HTMX and Streaming HTML</h2>
<p>I'm playing around with using <a href="https://htmx.org/">HTMX</a> and <a href="https://www.djangoproject.com/">Django's</a> ability to stream
<a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML">HTML</a> to improve the user experience. Basically, we'll load the static parts (like
the footer, navbar, etc.) of the page templates as soon as possible, and then load the data as it becomes available and
render its fragment of HTML. Not sure if this will be pushed to production or not until I do more testing, but it's
something worth looking into.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>metrontagger</category>
            <category>comictagger</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[November 2023 Update]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/november-2023-update</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/november-2023-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 13:29:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Issues Indexed]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="issues-indexed">Issues Indexed</h2>
<p>Not much user-facing development was done in November, but 10,612 issues were added to the database bringing the total
number of issues to <strong>88,244</strong>. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="2024-tasks">2024 Tasks</h2>
<p>I've started working on a list of items that I'm planning to work on in 2024. Here's a partial list:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Upgrade Server</p>
<p>Currently, the server is fairly underpowered (1 GiB Memory, 1 CPU, 25 GiB SSD, 1,000 GiB Transfer) but is able to
handle the current load without any particular issues. Based on the current user growth rate, I'm guessing I'll
finally need to upgrade sometime in 2024, I'm thinking a fairly minor bump should be sufficient (2 GiB Memory,
1CPU, 50 GiB SSD, 2,000 GiB Transfer)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Container Deployment</p>
<p>Before upgrading the server it makes sense to <em>finally</em> set up the project to use containers (preferably
<a href="https://podman.io/">Podman</a>) when deploying the website. If anyone wants to help
with <a href="https://github.com/bpepple/metron/issues/69">this</a>, that would be awesome.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Look into Open Collective for Future Funding</p>
<p>Eventually it will make sense to look at setting up something like
<a href="https://opencollective.com/opensource">Open Collective</a> to help with future server costs. Right now the server costs
around $14 a month (not including annual domain name &amp; email hosting costs) so it's not really an issue, but down the
road I probably won't want to cover all the costs of the project myself.</p>
<p>Glancing at the criteria needed for acceptance to the Open Source Collective, it looks like Metron meets most of them,
except having <em>100 stars</em> on <a href="https://github.com/">Github</a>. <em><strong>So, if you'd like to help the project, one easy
way would be to star the <a href="https://github.com/bpepple/metron">repository</a>.</strong></em></p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Manga / International Support</p>
<p>It would be nice to make a final decision on whether to support Manga and Non-U.S. issues, right now I'm inclined not
to but <em>if</em> we do add support it will necessitate some changes to the database for things like currencies, languages,
and such.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I'm sure there will be other smaller items (like tweaking the site's css and such), but these are most items I'll be
looking at in 2024. 🎉</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>metrontagger</category>
            <category>comictagger</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[October 2023 Update]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/october-2023-update</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/october-2023-update</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 10:04:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[New Indexed Issues Milestone]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-indexed-issues-milestone">New Indexed Issues Milestone</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://metron.cloud/">Metron Project</a> reached a milestone this month by having more than 77,000 issues added to
its database. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="metron-tagger-v164">Metron-Tagger v1.6.4</h2>
<h3 id="duplicate-page-removal">Duplicate Page Removal</h3>
<p>Just released a new version of <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/metron-tagger">Metron-Tagger</a>, which adds a new
experimental feature of finding / removing duplicate pages in a directory of comics. The feature will get the hashes for
all the pages of the comics in a directory, and then ask the user if the image should be removed from the comics. This
is done by using the user's system image viewer to display the duplicate image. Once the user has reviewed all the
duplicated images it will ask the user whether to write the changes to the comics and then prompt them if they also want
to update the <a href="https://anansi-project.github.io/docs/comicinfo/intro">ComicInfo.xml</a> (if it exists) for the page
changes.</p>
<p>This feature most likely will work best when running on a weekly basis, instead of on a <em><strong>whole</strong></em> comic collection,
since it's asking the user to review all the duplicate images <em>before</em> writing the changes. I'm planning on reworking
this to make it more feasible to use on a large comic collection, but that is pretty far down on my TODO list (but if
someone wants to work on this I'm more than willing to review a Pull Request).</p>
<p><strong>Note</strong>: I've been using this for the last month and haven't had any issues, but if you plan on using this I would
suggest backing up any files when using this initially, and verifying it works correctly for you since once the changes
are written they can't be undone! 💣</p>
<h3 id="miscellaneous-maintenance">Miscellaneous Maintenance</h3>
<p>The rest of v1.6.4 changes are primarily developer-side changes updating the toolsets for Metron-Tagger.</p>
<h2 id="comic-tagger">Comic-Tagger</h2>
<p><a href="https://github.com/comictagger/comictagger">Comic-Tagger</a> recently released
their <a href="https://github.com/comictagger/metron_talker">Metron-Talker</a> plugin which adds support for tagging any comic with
metadata from <a href="https://metron.cloud/">Metron</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>metrontagger</category>
            <category>comictagger</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Latest Happenings]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/latest-happenings</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/latest-happenings</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 13:24:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[New Indexed Issues Milestone]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="new-indexed-issues-milestone">New Indexed Issues Milestone</h2>
<p>The <a href="https://metron.cloud/">Metron Project</a> reached a milestone today by having 65,000 issues added to its database. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!</p>
<h2 id="post-api">POST API</h2>
<p>Been spending the last few months working on a POST API to make it easier to add/update information on Metron. Currently it's only available to users with Adminstrators permissions, but later this year I'll look at the feasability of making it more readily available.</p>
<h2 id="comic-vine-ids">Comic Vine ID's</h2>
<p>Another project I've been working on is adding <a href="https://comicvine.gamespot.com/">Comic Vine</a> identification numbers to the various resource items. This should help users match items between the two data sources. Currently, about 40% of the issues have been updated with this information and with any luck the majority of issues will be finished by the end of the month.</p>
<h2 id="comictagger">ComicTagger</h2>
<p>One of the developers of <a href="https://github.com/comictagger/comictagger">Comic Tagger</a> has been working on adding support for tagging digital comics with data from Metron, and hopefully in the next couple of months that merged.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>series</category>
            <category>api</category>
            <category>comicvine</category>
            <category>comictagger</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Limited Series Type]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/series-type-change</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/series-type-change</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 16:51:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Made a minor change to the series types available by consolidating mini & maxi-series to the new Limited Series type. There isn't a real definite value for mini and maxi series, and really it makes more sense to not bother differentiating them. So, I've gone ahead and migrated the existing data for this change, and users should see this change. If you have any questions or thoughts, don't hesitate to contact me.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Made a minor change to the <em><strong>series types</strong></em> available by consolidating <em><strong>mini &amp; maxi-series</strong></em> to the new <em><strong>Limited Series</strong></em> type. There isn't a real definite value for mini and maxi series, and really it makes more sense to not bother differentiating them. So, I've gone ahead and migrated the existing data for this change, and users should see this change. If you have any questions or thoughts, don't hesitate to contact <a href="mailto:bpepple@metron.cloud">me</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>series</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using Podman to Run GCD Database Locally]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/podman-gcd</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/podman-gcd</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Oct 2022 11:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[I've had a few users ask me how to run a local copy of the Grand Comics Database, so I figured I'd do a short write-up on how I do it.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I've had a few users ask me how to run a local copy of the <a href="https://www.comics.org/">Grand Comics Database</a>, so I figured I'd do a short write-up on how I do it.</p>
<p>I use <a href="https://podman.io/">Podman</a> for containers instead of <a href="https://www.docker.com/">Docker</a>, but the differences between them is fairly minimal and this should give you a good idea of how to do it. Anyway, let's get started!</p>
<p>First off, you'll want to download the most recent database dump from GCD which can be found <a href="https://www.comics.org/download/">here</a>. Once it's finished downloading, unzip the file:</p>
<pre><code>unzip current.zip -d /tmp/
</code></pre>
<p>You should see output similar to this:</p>
<pre><code>Archive:  current.zip
  inflating: /tmp/2022-10-01.sql   
</code></pre>
<p>Ok, now that we've got the data from gcd, let's create a <a href="https://www.mysql.com/">MySQL</a> container. We need to first pull a MySQL image, which can be done by running:</p>
<pre><code>podman pull docker.io/library/mysql:5.7
</code></pre>
<p>After it's done downloading the image, you can confirm:</p>
<pre><code>podman images
</code></pre>
<p>which should return output similar to this:</p>
<pre><code>bpepple@frodo ~ $ podman images mysql
REPOSITORY               TAG         IMAGE ID      CREATED       SIZE
docker.io/library/mysql  5.7         eb175b0743cc  19 hours ago  448 MB
</code></pre>
<p>Now we need to create the container. You'll want to replace user and mysql credentials with your own values. The <code>volume</code> flag is where on your filesystem you want to save the database. The <code>Z</code> suffix is used for systems, primarily <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/topics/linux/what-is-selinux">Red Hat</a>-based, that use <a href="https://www.redhat.com/en/topics/linux/what-is-selinux">SELinux</a>. If you don't use SELinux that can be dropped:</p>
<pre><code>podman run -d --name mysql -p 3306:3306 -e MYSQL_USER=bpepple -e MYSQL_PASSWORD=123456 -e MYSQL_DATABASE=gcd -e MYSQL_ROOT_PASSWORD=567890 --volume /home/bpepple/Storage/pods/mysql/:/var/lib/mysql:Z mysql:5.7
</code></pre>
<p>Now let's verify that the container was created and is running by using the following:</p>
<pre><code>podman ps
</code></pre>
<p>You should see output similar to this:</p>
<pre><code>bpepple@frodo ~ $ podman ps
CONTAINER ID  IMAGE                       COMMAND CREATED       STATUS           PORTS                  NAMES
400c957ae25d  docker.io/library/mysql:5.7 mysqld  7 seconds ago Up 7 seconds ago 0.0.0.0:3306-&gt;3306/tcp mysql
</code></pre>
<p>Now we just need to dump the data from GCD into the database. We can do this by running:</p>
<pre><code>cat /tmp/2022-10-01.sql | podman exec -i mysql /usr/bin/mysql -u root --password=567890 gcd
</code></pre>
<p>Depending on the specs of your machine, this might be a good time to grab some coffee, since the SQL dump is <strong>very</strong> large and will take awhile to finish. Once it's done, we can start using the database by attaching to the container:</p>
<pre><code>podman exec -it mysql mysql -ubpepple -p gcd
</code></pre>
<p>This command will prompt you for your password, and then you'll see the MySQL prompt where you can run a simple SQL statement like so:</p>
<pre><code> DESCRIBE gcd_issue;
</code></pre>
<p>Which should produce output similar to this:</p>
<pre><code>+----------------------------+---------------+------+-----+---------------------+----------------+
| Field                      | Type          | Null | Key | Default             | Extra          |
+----------------------------+---------------+------+-----+---------------------+----------------+
| id                         | int(11)       | NO   | PRI | NULL                | auto_increment |
| number                     | varchar(50)   | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| volume                     | varchar(50)   | NO   | MUL |                     |                |
| no_volume                  | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| display_volume_with_number | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| series_id                  | int(11)       | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| indicia_publisher_id       | int(11)       | YES  | MUL | NULL                |                |
| indicia_pub_not_printed    | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| brand_id                   | int(11)       | YES  | MUL | NULL                |                |
| no_brand                   | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| publication_date           | varchar(255)  | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| key_date                   | varchar(10)   | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| sort_code                  | int(11)       | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| price                      | varchar(255)  | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| page_count                 | decimal(10,3) | YES  |     | NULL                |                |
| page_count_uncertain       | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | 0                   |                |
| indicia_frequency          | varchar(255)  | NO   |     |                     |                |
| no_indicia_frequency       | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| editing                    | longtext      | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| no_editing                 | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| notes                      | longtext      | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| created                    | datetime      | NO   |     | 1901-01-01 00:00:00 |                |
| modified                   | datetime      | NO   | MUL | 1901-01-01 00:00:00 |                |
| deleted                    | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| is_indexed                 | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| isbn                       | varchar(32)   | NO   | MUL |                     |                |
| valid_isbn                 | varchar(13)   | NO   | MUL |                     |                |
| no_isbn                    | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| variant_of_id              | int(11)       | YES  | MUL | NULL                |                |
| variant_name               | varchar(255)  | NO   |     |                     |                |
| barcode                    | varchar(38)   | NO   | MUL |                     |                |
| no_barcode                 | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | 0                   |                |
| title                      | varchar(255)  | NO   | MUL |                     |                |
| no_title                   | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | 0                   |                |
| on_sale_date               | varchar(10)   | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| on_sale_date_uncertain     | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | 0                   |                |
| rating                     | varchar(255)  | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| no_rating                  | tinyint(1)    | NO   | MUL | NULL                |                |
| volume_not_printed         | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
| no_indicia_printer         | tinyint(1)    | NO   |     | NULL                |                |
+----------------------------+---------------+------+-----+---------------------+----------------+
40 rows in set (0.00 sec)

</code></pre>
<p>Great, we've got the database up and running! To logout from the container just type:</p>
<pre><code>\q
</code></pre>
<p>To stop the container, you would just use the following:</p>
<pre><code>podman stop mysql
</code></pre>
<p>And that's it! Podman has tons of niceties (like auto-updating images, using <a href="https://systemd.io/">systemd</a> for container start-ups, etc.) and I'd encourage you to read up on using some its many features. If it get some free time, I'll do a follow-up article about using <a href="https://www.python.org/">Python</a> to query the database and using that data for things like writing metadata to comic archives.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>podman</category>
            <category>mysql</category>
            <category>gcd</category>
            <category>grandcomicdatabase</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OS Upgrade]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/ubuntu-2204-lts</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/ubuntu-2204-lts</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2022 14:32:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Finally got around to upgrading the OS for Metron to Ubuntu 22.04.1 LTS, which overall, was fairly painless. Tests didn't find anything obviously broken, but if you do run across something that is, please open a bug for it. Thx!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finally got around to upgrading the OS for Metron to <a href="https://releases.ubuntu.com/22.04.1/">Ubuntu 22.04.1 LTS</a>, which overall, was fairly painless. Tests didn't find anything obviously broken, but if you do run across something that is, please open a <a href="https://github.com/bpepple/metron/issues/new/choose">bug</a> for it. Thx!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>server</category>
            <category>ubuntu</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Esak-1.3.2]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/esak-132</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/esak-132</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 10:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Did a quick release this morning of the python wrapper for the Marvel API, Esak, which adds an option to have the cache results expire after a user-defined number of days. To update to the latest version just run the following command:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did a quick release this morning of the python wrapper for the Marvel API, <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/esak">Esak</a>, which adds an option to have the cache results expire after a user-defined number of days. To update to the latest version just run the following command:</p>
<pre><code>pip3 install -U --user esak
</code></pre>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>marvel</category>
            <category>api</category>
            <category>python</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Darkseid-1.3.3]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/darkseid-133</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/darkseid-133</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 12:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Did a quick release today of Darkseid that fixes a bug which prevented exporting rar (.cbr) comics to zip files (.cbz). If you use Metron-Tagger and export rar files, it would be worthwhile to update Darkseid which can be done with the following command:]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Did a quick release today of <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/darkseid">Darkseid</a> that fixes a bug which prevented exporting rar (.cbr) comics to zip files (.cbz). If you use <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/metron-tagger">Metron-Tagger</a> and export rar files, it would be worthwhile to update Darkseid which can be done with the following command:</p>
<pre><code>pip3 install -U --user darkseid
</code></pre>
<p>As always if you run into any problems, don't hesitate to contact us on <a href="https://matrix.to/#/#metrondb:matrix.org">Matrix</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>cbz</category>
            <category>cbr</category>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>tagging</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trade Paperback / Collections Support]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/trade-paperback-collections-support</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/trade-paperback-collections-support</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jul 2022 15:35:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Marvel Masterworks Cover]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img alt="Marvel Masterworks Cover" src="https://metron-project.github.io/assets/images/marvel-masterworks-uncanny-xmen-1-114c858d5bb91b1f14ce68106e84c30a.jpg" width="450" height="150"></p>
<p>A user contacted me about adding <a href="https://metron.cloud/series/marvel-masterworks-the-uncanny-x-men-2003/">Marvel Masterworks: The Uncanny X-Men</a> series to <a href="https://metron.cloud/">Metron</a> since we have recently added support for trade paperbacks/collected editions. I figured this would be useful exercise since it would show me what parts of the process could be improved to make it easier.</p>
<p>Currently, the process requires the editor to add <em><strong>all</strong></em> creators, characters, teams, etc. manually for the reprinted issues associate with the collection, much like a regular issue. One obvious way to simplify this is to automatically <em><strong>add</strong></em> any characters, team, story titles, etc. for the issues being reprinted. Currently, I've written an <a href="https://github.com/bpepple/metron/blob/0d6268f92709ef886e49ffe2a134a0b6af3672f7/comicsdb/admin/issue.py#L145">admin action</a> to do this, but sometime in the future I need to expose this functionality so that <em><strong>anyone</strong></em> adding a Trade Paperback/Collection can save some time.</p>
<p>When I was creating Metron one of the choices I made was to add creators at an issue-level, and not at a story-level, since I wanted the process for adding an issue to be fairly simple. The downside to this approach is that adding information to a collection from an issue with multiple stories isn't really possible.😢</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>marvel</category>
            <category>masterworks</category>
            <category>x-men</category>
            <category>tpb</category>
            <category>collections</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[50,000 issues indexed]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/50000-issues</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/50000-issues</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[The Metron Project reached a milestone today by having 50,000 issues added to its database. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Metron Project reached a milestone today by having 50,000 issues added to its database. I wish to give big thanks to everyone who has helped with the project. Thanks!</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>database</category>
            <category>api</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MetronInfo.xml]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/welcome-metroninfo</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/welcome-metroninfo</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[So, one of the new projects I've been working on in my spare time is a new comic book xml schema called MetronInfo.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>So, one of the new projects I've been working on in my spare time is a new comic book xml schema called <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/metroninfo">MetronInfo</a>.</p>
<p>Currently, most applications use <a href="https://github.com/anansi-project/comicinfo">ComicInfo</a> which originated from the <a href="https://comicrack.en.softonic.com/">ComicRack</a> application, but due to it's history this format has some limitations like:</p>
<ul>
<li><strong>Poor handling of data.</strong> For example, cover date information that is split into separate integer types, instead of just using a date type.</li>
<li><strong>Limited types metadata stored.</strong> For example, when tagging a comic book archive with an application like <a href="https://github.com/comictagger/comictagger">ComicTagger</a> it would be useful to know where the metadata information was retrieved from (i.e. Comic Vine, GCD, Metron, etc.) and the resources identification number.</li>
<li><strong>Lack of documentation.</strong> The <a href="https://anansi-project.github.io/">Anansi Project</a> <em><strong>is</strong></em> working on improving this, tho.</li>
</ul>
<p>For now, the Anansi Project is working on documenting and extending (non-breaking changes) the ComicInfo schema, but in my opinion that time spent would be better spent on creating a new format not tied to a dead application. Due to the fairly unstructured nature of comic book archives it's trivial to tag one with the existing ComicInfo format <strong>and</strong> also a new format. That way users who use applications that only support ComicInfo.xml can still use them, but also gives them the option to use applications that could support the MetronInfo format.</p>
<p>My goals for MetronInfo.xml are:</p>
<ul>
<li>Fix some of the deficiencies of the ComicInfo format.</li>
<li>Add information to make it easier for Plex-like application to identify data (series, character, etc/) when importing comics into their application.</li>
<li>Document the elements clearly so their use is not ambiguous.</li>
</ul>
<p>Currently I'm working right now on finalizing the new format, and would appreciate any help or feedback from the comic book community in this. Feel free to leave suggestions either at the <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/metroninfo/discussions">Discussions Page</a> or contact use over on <a href="https://matrix.to/#/#metrondb:matrix.org">Matrix</a>.</p>
<p>Once the new format is finalized I plan on writing a tool that will create a MetronInfo.xml file for any existing comic book archive that was tagged with ComicTagger or <a href="https://github.com/Metron-Project/metron-tagger">Metron-Tagger</a>, and also retrieve any missing data from the source of information (Metron or Comic Vine).</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>comic</category>
            <category>metadata</category>
            <category>tagging</category>
            <category>comicvine</category>
            <category>comic-tagger</category>
            <category>anansi-project</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
            <link>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/welcome</link>
            <guid>https://metron-project.github.io/blog/welcome</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Welcome to the Metron Project! We'll be using this site to add some documentation and information about new project initiatives here.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to the Metron Project! We'll be using this site to add some documentation and information about new project initiatives here.
If you have any questions, don't hesitate to contact us on <a href="https://matrix.to/#/#metrondb:matrix.org">Matrix</a>.</p>]]></content:encoded>
            <category>metron</category>
            <category>comic</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>